

## Ilia Semukhin

# **Data Engineer**

Phone number: +351 920444299 | Email address: ilia.semukhin@gmail.com

**LinkedIn:** https://www.linkedin.com/in/iliasemukhin/

### ABOUT ME

I specialize in data analysis, database management, and building ETL processes. I implemented a DWH that integrated multiple data sources, saving over 2 million EUR through data insights. My skills include SQL, PostgreSQL, Python, Docker, CI/CD, AWS Cloud and Google Cloud, BigQuery, and using Power BI, Tableau, Superset and Looker for data visualization. I hold certifications in Google Data Analytics, Microsoft Power BI, and IBM Data Analyst, AWS and have a recommendation letter for my achievements.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

1 SEP 2023 – CURRENT Moscow, **Data Engineer** CARPRICE LLC

Website <a href="https://carprice.auction">https://carprice.auction</a>

- Analyzing large datasets to identify trends, creating interactive dashboards to communicate insights.
- Developing predictive models for sales forecasting and marketing optimization.
- Leveraging customer data for business insights, analyzing customer behavior and product performance.
- Managing ETL processes and DWH for data integration, ensuring efficient data storage and retrieval.
- Preparing concise analytical reports for stakeholders.

SEP 2018 - FEB 2022 Moscow, Russia

**LEGAL DEPARTMENT SPECIALIST ROSCOSMOS** 

Website https://roscosmos.ru/

Provided legal support for Roscosmos' construction projects, including facilities across Russia.

DEC 2012 - AUG 2018 Moscow, Russia

**BUSINESS LAWYER EVERGREEN LINE** 

Website <a href="https://www.evergreen-line.com/">https://www.evergreen-line.com/</a>

Legal support for business

JAN 2010 - NOV 2012 Moscow, Russia

**BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER SYNOVATE/IPSOS** 

Website <a href="https://www.ipsos.com/en-uk/europe">https://www.ipsos.com/en-uk/europe</a>

Marketing research business development, field work, data analysis, preparation of analytical reports.

## EDUCATION

2008 - 2014 Moscow, Russia

**BACHELOR OF ECONOMICS AND MARKETING** Russian Social State University

2015 - 2018 Kazan, Russia

MASTER OF LAWS Kazan State University

2023 Europe

IBM DATA ANALYST PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE IBM

2023 Europe

**DATA ANALYST** Google Career Certificates

2023 Europe

MICROSOFT POWER BI DATA ANALYST PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATE Microsoft

2023 Europe

**AWS CLOUD FUNDAMENTALS** Amazon Web Services

### DIGITAL SKILLS

